<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jawadsblog.netlify.app//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://jawadsblog.netlify.app//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2020-06-27T17:42:33+05:30</updated><id>https://jawadsblog.netlify.app//feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jawads Blog</title><subtitle>He is writing about technology, Politics and experience as a journal  for documentation things that he learned, meet him &lt;a href=&quot;syedjawadakhtar.github.io&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;@syedjawadakhtar&lt;/a&gt;.</subtitle><author><name>Syed Jawad Akhtar</name><email>syedjawadakhtar@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">First blog</title><link href="https://jawadsblog.netlify.app//first-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First blog" /><published>2020-05-08T03:18:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-08T03:18:00+05:30</updated><id>https://jawadsblog.netlify.app//first-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jawadsblog.netlify.app//first-blog/">&lt;p&gt;Well starting a new thing has always been a long procrastinating journey. But in the end, we just have to get up and accomplish it. As I am doing right now by writing this at 3 am in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-start-from-the-start&quot;&gt;Let’s start from the start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-inspiration&quot;&gt;My inspiration&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A pen is mightier than a sword!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess there were a lot of people to inspire me to start my own space for blogging. From senior developers like &lt;a href=&quot;https://kushaldas.in/&quot;&gt;Kushal Das&lt;/a&gt; to outstanding peers like &lt;a href=&quot;https://rj722.github.io/&quot;&gt;Rahul Jha&lt;/a&gt; and amazing juniors like &lt;a href=&quot;https://pnijhara.me/about/&quot;&gt;Prajjwal Nijhara&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://prateekj117.me&quot;&gt;Prateek Jain&lt;/a&gt;. Even though it was only about their websites that intrigued me because I have been writing in my diaries/notepads whenever I needed to relieve myself from a mind-bothering idea. But then writing it in a public domain is totally a different thing. It is more about making clear points about the topic and not just blurting out the chaos from your mind. So to learn this art, I picked a blogging Jekyll-theme online and started it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S: Do make your reading comfortable by trying the dual-mode of the website from the top-left corner of the website&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-topics-i-may-pen-down&quot;&gt;The topics I may pen down:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: The categories may change with respect to time due to any reasons.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m a computer engineering student and my writings wil be about my learnings in the field of robotics, artificial intelligence, and self-driving vehicles. This may be in the form of &lt;em&gt;experiences&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;tutorials&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;strong&gt;General psychology:&lt;/strong&gt; I have been interested in the human mind and how does it take actions consciously and/or subconsciously. I have been reading books like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Power-Your-Subconscious-Mind-ebook/dp/B0773RQ55P/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=The+Power+of+Your+Subconscious+Mind&amp;amp;qid=1588710685&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot;&gt;The Power of the Subconscious Mind&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Distracted-Mind-Ancient-Brains-High-Tech/dp/0262034948&quot;&gt;The Distracted Mind: Ancient Brains in Tech World&lt;/a&gt;. So most probably I may be discussing about my &lt;em&gt;observations&lt;/em&gt; about &lt;em&gt;actions&lt;/em&gt; in this world from different prespective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;strong&gt;Politics:&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve had become active on Twitter (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/syedjawadakhtar&quot;&gt;my handle&lt;/a&gt;) since my university started being targetted by media houses and political parties in 2018. Since then my mind has been picking up a lot of topics with the constant unrest in the country. Here I’ll express my views about the topics, and anyone is welcome for having a logical discussion on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;to-know-more-about-me&quot;&gt;To know more about me&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more about me, please do check out my main website &lt;a href=&quot;https://syedjawadakhtar.github.io&quot;&gt;syedjawadakhtar.github.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://syedjawadakhtar.github.io/#contact&quot;&gt;contact page&lt;/a&gt; to connect with me on different platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you and see you soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Syed Jawad Akhtar</name><email>syedjawadakhtar@gmail.com</email></author><category term="general" /><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Well starting a new thing has always been a long procrastinating journey. But in the end, we just have to get up and accomplish it. As I am doing right now by writing this at 3 am in the morning.</summary></entry></feed>